3:45 okay let's get started well this
3:45好的，让我们开始吧
one really has an echo in this room okay
这个房间里真的有回声
so today's session is going to be
所以今天的会议将是
talking about this relationship between
谈论之间的这种关系
jacquard EEE and mica profile it's
提花EEE和云母轮廓
probably the number one question that I
大概是我的头号问题
get whether I'm at conferences I might
知道我是否参加会议
be visiting a jug and a you know nearby
来一壶，你知道附近
user group even within IBM I I'll have
用户群，即使在IBM中
people come up and I ask well what what
人们来了，我问好什么
is this relationship so I wrote a blog
是这种关系，所以我写了一个博客
about it
关于它
and I got quite a bit of attention and
我得到了很多关注，
so then I kind of turned it what's that
所以我有点转过头了
oh I was little out of the picture sorry
哦，我一点都不在意
so threw me off okay so even at IBM I
所以把我赶走了，即使在IBM I
was getting questions about what is the
有人问什么是
future or the relationship between these
未来或这些之间的关系
two and so I had this blog and I decided
两个，所以我有了这个博客，我决定
to turn it into a presentation I this is
把它变成一个演示文稿，我这是
the the first time that I proposed it as
我第一次提出它是
a presentation and I did it both at
一个演示文稿，我在
eclipse cann you're up here and at
食不能你在这里和在
JavaOne or oracle code one lo and behold
JavaOne或oracle代码一目了然
it gets accepted at both and they are of
双方都接受了
the same week so I asked our de for all
同一周，所以我要求我们的所有
of a websphere to cover my session out
Websphere覆盖我的会议
at Oracle code one so that's why his
在Oracle代码一处，这就是为什么他
name is up on the charts I had to do all
图表上有名字，我必须做所有
the work but he you know he gets to
工作，但他你知道他去
present it I would it Oracle code one so
呈现它我会为Oracle代码编写一个
let's just look at this question what's
让我们看看这个问题是什么
next well one thing that we want to do
接下来，我们要做的一件事
is I have better conference scheduling
我有更好的会议安排吗
next year so that we don't have this
明年，以便我们没有这个
type of overlap so I know that eclipse
重叠的类型，所以我知道日食
con Europe can't change we've got a
骗局欧洲无法改变，我们有一个
contract in place so that this is not
合同到位，所以这不是
moving it's been the same week in
搬来已经是同一周了
October for years so hopefully Oracle
十月这么多年，希望甲骨文
figures out their game and they can move
弄清楚他们的比赛，他们可以移动
it to a better time frame
到更好的时间框架
just a little bit about me I've been
关于我的一小部分
working in this space in Java EE like a
在Java EE中像
profile lower components of Java EE
剖析Java EE的下层组件
which APA and JC a I've been at this for
我去过哪个APA和JC
several years I am from the IBM
我来自IBM几年
Rochester lab and one thing that I've
罗切斯特实验室和我做过的一件事
been finding is as I've been talking
我一直在寻找
with various people around the
与周围的人
conference they're not sure where
会议上，他们不确定在哪里
Rochester Minnesota is they've heard of
明尼苏达州罗切斯特（Rochester Minnesota）听说过
Rochester New York but not Rochester
纽约罗切斯特，但不是罗彻斯特
Minnesota so I thought I'd show where
明尼苏达州，所以我想我会告诉哪里
that is Minnesota is kind of in the
那是明尼苏达州的那种
central United States up near Canada but
美国中部靠近加拿大，但
not quite but then people have asked
不完全是，但后来人们问
well what's known you know what besides
好吧，众所周知，你还知道什么
IBM what else is in Rochester so maybe
IBM罗切斯特还有什么，所以也许
you have heard of the Mayo Clinic
您听说过梅奥诊所
so the Mayo Clinic it's a national world
所以梅奥诊所是一个民族世界
renowned medical facility in that
那个著名的医疗机构
started in Rochester Minnesota back in
始于明尼苏达州罗切斯特市
Java 1 2015 yen and I we actually did a
Java 1 2015日元，我实际上做了
joint session at JavaOne
JavaOne联合会议
and we asked this question as Java EE s
我们以Java EE的形式问了这个问题
is still relevant or is it an elephant
还是相关的还是大象
and the idea behind that is we didn't
而背后的想法是我们没有
know what was happening with Java EE we
知道Java EE发生了什么
did not see the progress that we
没有看到我们的进步
expected to see Java EE 8 of course
预计当然会看到Java EE 8
wasn't out yet wasn't even defined yet
还没出来还没定义
at that time and you know we just didn't
那时你知道我们只是没有
see the activity so we didn't know what
看到活动，所以我们不知道
was really happening and we knew
真的发生了，我们知道
microservices was really taking off and
微服务真的起飞了，
what are we going to do from an
我们该怎么办
enterprise Java perspective so that was
企业Java角度
the end of 2015 because September
2015年底，因为9月
October time frame early in 2016 it was
2016年初的10月是
at devoxx UK and a few of us got
在devoxx UK，我们中的一些人
together and started talking about this
一起开始谈论这个
problem so what are we going to do about
问题，我们该怎么办
supporting microservices in an
支持微服务
enterprise Java space the thing that we
企业Java空间我们所需要的东西
came up with was micro profile we
想出了微观概况
actually came up with the name if you
其实想出了这个名字
were at my earlier talk you know Jakarta
在我之前的谈话中，您知道雅加达
came a little bit later
过了一会儿
Micra profile we actually came up with
我们实际上想出的Micra个人资料
the name first before we actually
这个名字先于我们
defined the content we knew we wanted to
定义了我们想要的内容
support micro services so it's a micro
支持微服务，所以它是微服务
services profile as what we thought of
我们认为的服务概况
at the time we knew that this new
当时我们知道
community we needed it to be or the this
社区，我们需要它成为或
new project we needed it to be community
新项目，我们需要它成为社区
driven we need people to participate we
驱使我们需要人们参与
don't we don't we didn't want one
不，我们不想要一个
particular vendor or person to be
特定的卖方或个人
driving the effort we wanted a joint
推动我们想要共同努力
community effort have it very
社区的努力
transparent very open open conversations
透明的非常公开的对话
open forums open discussions and I think
打开论坛，打开讨论，我认为
you know overall we have accomplished
你知道总体上我们已经完成了
that the other key thing is we decided
另一个关键是我们决定
we didn't want reference implementations
我们不希望参考实现
we knew we wanted to do specifications
我们知道我们想做规格
API s and tcks
API和tcks
what we didn't want to have a single
我们不想有一个
reference implementation that all the
参考实施的所有
vendors would have to participate in
供应商必须参加
creation and support of so what that
创造和支持什么
really means is that as we develop a
真正的意思是，随着我们发展
specification maybe maybe red hat is
规格也许戴红色帽子是
driving one of the specifications and so
驾驶规范之一等等
they develop a compatible implementation
他们开发了兼容的实现
using wildfly or thorne tail now that's
现在使用野生蝇或刺尾巴
just fine and then maybe iBM is leading
很好，然后也许iBM正在领先
another specification and we do a
另一个规范，我们做一个
compatible implementation in open
开放兼容的实现
Liberty that's what we decided was okay
我们决定的自由就可以了
we didn't want to have a single
我们不想有一个
reference implementation and the other
参考实施及其他
key thing is we wanted more nimble
关键是我们要更敏捷
iterative processing we were used to
我们习惯于迭代处理
Java EE it took years for a new platform
Java EE建立新平台花了好几年
to come out it took years for a
出来花了好几年
component release I mean even like a
组件发布我的意思是甚至像
maintenance release that would take
需要的维护版本
years to go through that whole process
整个过程需要很多年
and we didn't want that for one thing
而且我们不想一件事
because it takes so much time and
因为要花很多时间
resource but Mike your services was
资源，但麦克您的服务是
moving so quickly there's no way that
如此迅速地移动，是不可能的
we'd be able to start to catch up if we
如果我们能够赶上
didn't have a more nimble process so
没有更灵活的过程，所以
those were the three key characteristics
这些是三个关键特征
that we were driving for with micro
我们为微型车而努力
profile so if you remember
个人资料，因此，如果您还记得
we talked about it early 2016 at devoxx
我们在devoxx于2016年初谈论了它
UK I think that's a February March
英国，我认为那是二月三月
timeframe by September of that year we
那年9月的时间表
had determined as a team we're going to
已经确定我们要成为一个团队
announce micro profile 1.0 and what
宣布Micro Profile 1.0以及什么
better location to do it than at JavaOne
比在JavaOne上更好的位置
so that's what we wanted to do at
这就是我们想要做的
JavaOne of course none of our sessions
Java当然没有我们的会议
got accepted so we weren't able to go in
被接受，所以我们无法进去
and actually have a session that
并有一个会议
announced it so as a community we had
宣布它为一个社区
actually rent another room at another
实际上在另一个地方租了另一个房间
hotel and we passed all cards and we
酒店，我们通过了所有卡，我们
said hey we're gonna have a little
说，嘿，我们要去一点
announcement you know come on over and
你知道的公告来了，
you know we're going to announce this
你知道我们要宣布这一点
Micra profile 1.0 we had a very good
Micra profile 1.0我们有一个很好的
turnout now maybe it was because we also
现在的投票率也许是因为我们也
offered a free lunch at the hotel I
我在酒店提供免费午餐
don't know but we had about 120 people
不知道，但我们有大约120个人
show up and so we saw an interest that
出现，所以我们看到了一种兴趣
really helped us continue because we
真的帮助我们继续前进，因为我们
really didn't know I mean we knew as
真的不知道我是说我们知道
vendors we needed to do something what
供应商，我们需要做些什么
it was very good to get that input from
很好地从中获取输入
the customers so at that time all that
当时的客户
we define micro profile were these three
我们定义微观轮廓是这三个
features out of Java EE the CDI jax-rs
Java EE中的功能CDI jax-rs
and json p and and that was it that we
和json p，而这就是我们
said that's the minimum that you need to
说那是你需要的最低要求
create a micro micro service okay now
现在创建一个微服务吧
flash forward two years two years just
快闪两年两年
pretty small timeframe just last week we
上周我们的时间非常短
announced Mike a profile 2.1 that's our
宣布Mike的个人资料2.1
seventh platform release in two years
两年内第七次平台发布
and seventeenth component release with
和第十七个组件发布
open tracing 1.2 now you know from our
打开跟踪1.2，现在您从我们知道
perspective that's pretty impressive in
令人印象深刻的观点
a two year time frame shake it out that
两年的时间框架将其震撼
many revs of different specifications
许多不同规格的转速
updates to tcks updates through the API
通过API更新tcks更新
s and compatible implementations the
和兼容的实现
only way that we can mark a
我们可以标记一个的唯一方法
specification is being complete is if we
规范是否完整是
have a compatible implementation that
具有兼容的实现
passes in TCK
通过TCK
so this from our perspective is pretty
所以从我们的角度来看这很漂亮
impressive for a micro profile we still
令人印象深刻的微观轮廓，我们仍然
have some things on our backlog I mean
我的意思是有些积压的东西
we're not done we've got other things
我们还没有完成，我们还有其他事情
that we're working on we've got some
我们正在努力，我们有一些
reactive work that we're doing we're
我们正在做的反应性工作
looking at how does Micah profile fit in
看米卡的轮廓如何适合
with a service mesh or sto there's some
与服务网格或有一些
stuff being done with concurrency
并发完成的事情
there's stuff being done there was a
有事情要做，有一个
session earlier this week on
会议于本周初
long-running activities or long-running
长期运行或长期运行
transactions if that makes more sense
交易是否更有意义
and we also have other updates for our
而且我们还有其他更新
current components and all these are in
当前组件，所有这些都在
the works now I should point out the
现在的作品，我应该指出
chart deck that I will be posting has a
我将要发布的图表平台有一个
corresponding page for every one of
每一个对应的页面
these technologies it gives a little bit
这些技术给了一点
of background on each one with links to
每个链接的背景
the project and links to our github and
该项目并链接到我们的github和
so that way you can look up more
这样您可以查找更多
information if you want but since I have
信息，如果你想要，但因为我有
to cover both topics today I can't go
涵盖这两个主题今天我不能去
into the detail on every one of them so
深入到每个细节
I've mentioned about compatible
我提到过兼容
implementations you'll see that's how we
您将看到的实现就是我们
have over ten various compatible
有十多种兼容
implementations yes oh I saw John back
是的，哦，我看到了约翰
there pointing I thought okay what's he
那里指向我以为他是什么
pointing at I'm sorry about that thank
指着我很抱歉
you for letting me know okay so the
您让我知道还可以
compatible implementations this is what
兼容的实现，这就是
I was saying we don't have reference
我是说我们没有参考
implementations the URL that's at the
实现位于
bottom of this page if you go out there
如果您去那里，则在此页底部
you can see the exact version with links
您可以看到带有链接的确切版本
to every compatible implementation for
每个兼容的实现
the corresponding component releases as
相应的组件发布为
well as the platform releases and the
以及平台版本和
page goes on for quite a while because
页面持续了一段时间，因为
of all of this activity from all of
所有这些活动中
these groups that are supporting micro
这些支持微型的团体
profile
轮廓
okay so that's kinda a little bit about
好吧，那有点
micro profile now I gotta talk a little
微型个人资料现在我要谈一点
bit about jacquard EEE before I start
在开始之前先介绍一下提花EEE
you know talking about the relationship
你知道谈论这种关系
between the two so if you remember Java
在两者之间，所以如果您还记得Java
well our discussions with micro profile
以及我们与微观个人资料的讨论
kind of started late 2015 but really
开始于2015年末，但实际上
took off in 2016 2017 Oracle was trying
在2016年起飞2017年Oracle正在尝试
to see in the light they're seeing all
看到他们看到的一切
the activity with micro profile they see
他们看到的带有微轮廓的活动
all these vendors jumping on board with
所有这些供应商都参与其中
it they were seeing the progress that
他们看到了进步
we're making this micro profile and
我们正在制作此微型配置文件，
they're kind of saying okay we got do
他们在说好吧，我们要做
something different with Java EE so they
Java EE有所不同，所以他们
approached a few of us vendors and said
接触了我们一些供应商并说
um what would you think if we went open
嗯，如果我们开门，你会怎么想
source with Java EE and it was like we
Java EE的源代码，就像我们
just said wonderful I mean we have been
只是说太好了，我的意思是我们一直
wanting to get Java EE out of Oracle's
希望将Java EE从Oracle淘汰
tight grip for a long time so for them
长时间握紧，对他们来说
to propose this we thought it was just a
提出这个，我们认为那只是一个
fantastic idea now if you've been
如果您曾经
listening to the various sessions this
听各种会议
week this is not an easy task going from
周这不是一件容易的事
basically I shouldn't say proprietary
基本上我不应该说专有的
but there's a lot of proprietary tooling
但是有很多专有工具
in the TCK was proprietary there's a lot
在TCK中是专有的
of proprietary information along with
专有信息以及
some of the community driven stuff from
一些社区推动的东西来自
Java EE that has to move in to this new
必须迁移到新版本中的Java EE
Eclipse space with Jakarta EE and it
使用Jakarta EE及其它的Eclipse空间
takes quite a bit of time the thing that
事情花了很多时间
we were working on is we got to get all
我们正在努力的是我们必须全力以赴
of our projects within Java EE move them
我们在Java EE中的项目将其移动
over to eclipse and get them through the
遮住食，使他们通过
process you'll notice that we're doing
过程中，您会注意到我们在做
pretty good you know most of the
很好，您知道大多数
projects are at 80% what that means is
项目占80％，这意味着
the projects have all been provisioned
项目已全部配置
all the code has been moved over we are
所有代码都移到了我们
able to build it we're able to test it
能够构建它，我们能够对其进行测试
but what we haven't done in most cases
但是大多数情况下我们还没有做
yet is doing an eclipse review or an
却正在进行日食检查或
eclipse release and there
月食释放和那里
a process associated with that you'll
与之相关的过程
see that we have a few of them that have
看到我们有一些
made that milestone several of those
使那个里程碑成为其中的几个
were existing Eclipse projects so they
是现有的Eclipse项目，所以他们
knew how to do an eclipse release like
知道如何做蚀发布
yes and with json be JSONP and eclipse
是的，使用json是JSONP和eclipse
link but you also notice there's two
链接，但您还注意到有两个
other ones jax-rs and servlet and they
其他的jax-rs和servlet，他们
have figured out all the process in
弄清楚了所有的过程
order to do a release within eclipse now
现在就在eclipse中发布
in order to do the release one of the
为了做释放之一
things that we need is a CI CD pipeline
我们需要的是CI CD管道
and this has been a major piece of work
这是一项重要的工作
for us every one of those projects that
对我们来说，那些项目中的每一个
I just had up there 39 of them every one
我每个人只有39个
of them probably have three or four
他们中可能有三四个
repositories github repositories and
仓库github仓库和
every one of those needs a Jenkins
每个人都需要詹金斯
pipeline in order to do nightly builds
进行每晚构建的管道
and then do release builds just a I I am
然后在第二天上午发布版本
really impressed with the progress and I
进步给我留下了深刻的印象，我
know Dimitri is the one from Oracle he's
知道Dimitri是来自Oracle的那个人
one that's been driving a lot of this
一个推动了很多
work but it really is a community effort
工作，但这确实是社区的努力
where multiple teams multiple people are
多人多人的地方
involved and when I was first you know I
参与其中，当我刚开始时，你知道我
had this as a holding spot in my chart
在我的图表中将此作为保留点
deck and when I was first putting this
甲板，当我第一次放这个
together about two weeks ago that right
大约两个星期前在一起
up there um let's get the light rate
嗯，让我们来获取光速
right right there the number done that
正确，正确的数字
says 81 when I first put this chart
我第一次输入此图表时说81
together it said five okay that was just
在一起说五个好，那只是
like two weeks ago maybe maybe two and a
像两个星期前，也许是两个和一个
half weeks ago okay so this is 81 I did
半个星期前好吧，这是81我做了
this cut and paste
剪切粘贴
last Friday before I got on the plane
上周五，在我上飞机之前
and I thought just this morning I
我以为就是今天早上
thought well where are we at now you can
想好了，我们现在在哪里可以
see we're 98 and we're down to just one
看到我们已经98岁了，我们只剩下一个
more to do over here that that needs to
需要在这里做更多的事情
be assigned so we're making fantastic
被分配，所以我们做得很棒
progress on getting this complete so
在完成这个方面的进展，所以
you're kind of wondering all what does
你有点想知道所有做什么
this really have to do with the whole
这确实与整体有关
process well the big thing here we want
处理好我们想要的大事情
to get Eclipse GlassFish
获得Eclipse GlassFish
and we want it to be Java EE 8 compliant
我们希望它兼容Java EE 8
in order to do that we want to make sure
为了做到这一点，我们要确保
that we are building with everything
我们正在建立一切
within Eclipse so we want all of these
在Eclipse中，因此我们希望所有这些
components I mean all of those
组件，我是说所有这些
components and all those repositories to
组件和所有这些存储库
be building Eclipse artifacts so that we
正在构建Eclipse工件，以便我们
can build Eclipse GlassFish so just this
可以构建Eclipse GlassFish
past weekend we got the RC one out for
过去的周末，我们得到了RC
Eclipse GlassFish 5.1 and from our
Eclipse GlassFish 5.1和我们的
perspective that was a major
主要的观点
accomplishment to have that ready now we
现在准备的成就
still have to complete the rest of the
仍然必须完成其余的
ECI CD tasks and then well you know
ECI CD任务，然后您知道
we'll continue I would guess we're
我们会继续，我想我们会
probably going to have several RC
大概会有几个RC
candidates before this is actually done
实际完成之前的候选人
but we're making progress
但是我们正在进步
on making a final Eclipse GlassFish 5.1
制作最终的Eclipse GlassFish 5.1
the other thing that's been taking up
另一件事正在占用
quite a bit of our time is defining a
我们很多时间都在定义
new specification process so since we're
新的规范流程，因为我们
kind of taking over for the JCP we need
接管我们需要的JCP
something that is more stringent than
比这更严格的东西
basically what we do is make a profile
基本上我们要做的是建立个人资料
ours is you'll find out a little bit
我们的是你会发现一点点
ours is a little bit more in loose but
我们的比较宽松
jacquard EEE
提花EEE
they need a more defined process there's
他们需要更明确的流程
more to own in this case and so we need
在这种情况下还有更多拥有权，因此我们需要
a process that will be a little bit
这个过程会有点
closer to what the JCP had defined we
更接近JCP定义的
have a public draft available I would
有一个公共草案我会
really urge everybody if you have any
真的要敦促大家，如果有的话
interest in Java EE Jakarta EE please
请对Java EE感兴趣Jakarta EE
take a look at the process even if
看一下这个过程，即使
you're you know if you feel like I hate
你知道你是否讨厌我
process I mean I'm not a big fan of it
过程我的意思是我不喜欢它
either but if you take a look at it just
要么，但如果你看看它
to see if it's something that you know
看看你是否知道
will or will not work for you for our
将为您或不会为我们工作
projects as we're going forward we would
随着我们前进的项目，我们将
appreciate the input we're cutting off
感谢我们切断的输入
the review period at the end of October
十月底的审查期
and we then will have to go through
然后我们将不得不经历
hopefully we you know we're not gonna
希望我们知道你不会
get a ton of review comments I make us
收到大量我给我们的评论
start over again and hopefully we can
重新开始，希望我们可以
you know get those merged in and we can
你知道把那些合并，我们可以
get a
得到
more final draft put out we are lucky
最后的草案已经发布，我们很幸运
because we've got a project that has
因为我们有一个项目
volunteered to be a guinea pig so it's a
自愿做豚鼠，所以它是一个
new project it's a well it's an existing
新项目，很好，现有
project within eclipse but it has an
eclipse中的项目，但它有一个
implementation so what we're doing is
实施，所以我们要做的是
they are going to create a new
他们将创建一个新的
specification project the proposal is
提案的规格项目是
public it's already out there and
公开它已经在那里
they're going to try to follow our
他们将尝试遵循我们的
process that we're defining and
我们正在定义的过程
hopefully using that process we can
希望使用该过程，我们可以
figure out okay where are the bumps in
弄清楚好吗？
our process and where are the bumps with
我们的过程以及颠簸在哪里
the jano SQL and let's see if we can
jano SQL，让我们看看是否可以
work this out so the team has been very
解决这个问题，所以团队一直非常
good to work with and they're willing to
很高兴与他们合作，他们愿意
get a few bumps and bruises as we go
前进时遇到一些颠簸和擦伤
through this we have other things in our
通过这个，我们还有其他的东西
pipeline of course after we get the
当然，我们得到
specification present even say after
规范提出后甚至说
because we're already working on these
因为我们已经在研究这些
things we have to figure out what's
我们必须弄清楚是什么
going to be our TCK compliance process
将成为我们的TCK合规流程
ok the JCP had one what is going to be
好，JCP有一个将要发生的事情
ours the TCK license how are we going to
我们的TCK许可证
license at TCK so that we can protect a
在TCK获得许可，以便我们保护
brand of jakarta EEE we have to define
我们必须定义雅加达EEE的品牌
that and the specification license so
那和规格许可证
that you know a similar type thing if we
如果我们知道您知道类似类型的事情
have people vendors projects that want
有需要的人员供应商项目
to implement the specifications coming
实施即将到来的规范
out of Jakarta EEE
从雅加达EEE
what's that licensing model because we
那是什么许可模式，因为我们
need to protect the IP flows through
需要保护通过的IP流
this whole process ok so now I kind of
这整个过程还可以，所以现在我有点
introduced both a little bit on micro
介绍了一些关于微
profile a little bit on Jakarta EE so
在Jakarta EE上进行一些配置
what's what's similar between the two of
两者之间有什么相似之处
them well one of them is we're both I
他们很好，其中之一是我们都是我
mean if you read our missions they
意思是如果您阅读我们的任务，他们
almost sound identical we are both
听起来差不多，我们俩
interested in micro service development
对微服务开发感兴趣
and cloud native Java ok key aspects of
和云原生Java的关键方面
our mission statements we both want more
我们的使命宣言我们都想要更多
agile development practices we've all
我们都有敏捷开发实践
grown up with a JCP in the headaches and
在JCP的陪伴下长大，
the length of time that it takes to get
花费的时间长度
through that so what can we do better
这样我们可以做得更好
this time around and we want the
这次，我们想要
code first mentality okay we want proven
编码第一心态好吧，我们要证明
concepts to get into these
这些概念
specifications the example that I use if
规范我使用的示例
you think back this goes back a ways
你回想这回去的方式
but j2ee one point but I don't know two
但是j2ee有一点，但我不知道两点
or three they defined an entity beam
或三个，他们定义了实体光束
model for EJ B's that was defined
定义的EJ B的模型
without any empirical evidence that the
没有任何经验证据
coding would ever work and that was just
编码将永远可行，那仅仅是
a failure every implementation of EJB
EJB的每个实现都失败
entity beans from all the different
来自所有不同的实体bean
vendors they were not compatible at all
他们根本不兼容的供应商
look at the other half of that EJB three
看一下EJB的另一半
with JP a came out in Java EE 5 now
与JP一起在Java EE 5中问世了
that's a success story but why was that
那是一个成功的故事，但是为什么呢
successful it was because it was based
成功是因为它基于
off of existing things happening in the
在发生的事情上
industry with especially hibernate with
行业特别是休眠
JPA and they participated in the
JPA和他们参加了
definition of that spec and that has
该规范的定义，并具有
been extremely successful from a
从一个非常成功的
persistence standpoint ok so I'm putting
持久性的立场好，所以我把
this chart back up because this is what
备份此图表，因为这就是
we kind of started with with micro
我们从微开始
profile and I think it kind of it still
个人资料，我认为还是这样
kind of applies to the Jakarta ee work
适用于Jakarta EE工作
we are very community driven there's a
我们是社区推动的
lot of different vendors and individuals
许多不同的供应商和个人
projects that are working on both
两者都在工作的项目
projects both micro profile and Jakarta
投影微轮廓和雅加达
EE the idea of no reference
EE无参考的想法
implementations as we've been working on
我们一直在努力的实现
Jakarta EE we brought that idea over
雅加达EE我们把这个想法带了过来
from micro profile they bought into it
从他们购买的微型资料中
so the Jakarta EE team says ok no
所以Jakarta EE小组说好吧
reference implementation now do you want
您现在想要参考实施
to clarify something because I'm
澄清一些事情，因为我
guessing some people are wondering
猜到有人在想
because I had mentioned GlassFish before
因为我之前提到过GlassFish
it's like ok isn't GlassFish the
好像还可以，不是GlassFish
reference implementation it is the
参考实现
reference implementation for Java EE 8
Java EE 8的参考实现
we have to get that up and running
我们必须启动并运行
within eclipse so that we have a Java EE
在eclipse中，以便我们拥有Java EE
eight reference implementation to match
八个参考实现相匹配
ok after that point when we start
好的，那点之后，当我们开始
defining additional Jakarta ee9 or
定义其他Jakarta ee9或
individual components
个别组件
GlassFish maybe it will be around I mean
GlassFish也许会在我的周围
you know and still in use but maybe
您知道并且仍在使用中，但也许
we'll use a wild fly or thorn tale as an
我们将使用野生苍蝇或荆棘故事作为
implementation okay so that's going
实施还可以，所以
forward
向前
but we need GlassFish to be Java EE
但是我们需要GlassFish成为Java EE
eight compliant and the other item here
八个兼容，另一个在这里
the lightweight iterative processes we
我们的轻量级迭代过程
know that we cannot have Jakarta EE move
知道我们不能让雅加达EE行动
as fast as what we've been doing this
和我们一直在做的一样快
micro profile absolutely understand that
微个人资料绝对了解
but we do need a quicker than what we
但是我们确实需要比我们更快的速度
did with the JCP and Java EE so it's all
使用JCP和Java EE完成了所有工作
relative I think is the way to look at
我认为是相对的方式
it okay so some of the differences and
好的，所以有些差异和
I'm already kind of touched on a couple
我已经被一对夫妇感动了
of these so Microsoft I Microsoft
这些，所以Microsoft I Microsoft
actually is a member of this so but I
实际上是这个成员，所以我
meant Micra profile we have had a very
意味着我们的Micra个人资料
well-established iterative release
完善的迭代发布
process as I mentioned seven major
正如我提到的七个主要过程
releases seventeen component releases
发布十七个组件版本
Jakarta EE there's no way they could
Jakarta EE无法实现
keep up with that we are looking at
跟上我们正在看的
maybe one or one or maybe two major
也许一或一或两个主要
releases per year it might just be one
每年的发行量可能只是一个
okay it's a different scale Jakarta ee
好吧，这是不同比例的雅加达ee
is so much larger than micro profile we
比微观轮廓大得多
have to keep that in mind it's not going
必须记住这不会
to match exactly the other thing micah
完全匹配米迦
profile was never meant to be a
个人资料从来都不是一个
standards body we never had that intent
我们从未有过这样的意图
the idea with micah profile was to
弥迦简介的想法是
innovate and if and when something
创新，是否以及何时
should become a standard then we would
应该成为一个标准，那么我们将
move it forward to the appropriate
将其移至适当的位置
standards body jakarta ee can't can't
标准机构雅加达EE无法做到
use that quite that same model because
使用完全相同的模型，因为
they're replacing the JCP so we need
他们正在取代JCP，所以我们需要
something that is much more stringent
更严格的东西
than what we have with micro profile
比我们的微轮廓
and the reason for that is to protect
原因是为了保护
the brand jacquard EEE is a valuable
提花品牌的EEE是有价值的
brand and we need to be able to protect
品牌，我们需要能够保护
it Micah profile yes we do have a brand
它的Micah个人资料是的，我们确实有一个品牌
it's all trademarked but we are doing
这都是商标，但我们正在做
everything on the honor system we've had
我们拥有的荣誉系统上的所有内容
implementations being produced by
由实施产生
colleges and universities and they come
高校和他们来
in and they claim that
在他们声称
yeah we've passed these tests we say
是的，我们已经通过了这些测试，我们说
great put your name on our wiki the wiki
伟大的把你的名字放在我们的维基上
is wide open they can go ahead and put
敞开着，他们可以继续前进
it in put links in and we just trust
它放在链接中，我们只是相信
them so it's all on the honor system
他们，所以一切都在荣誉系统上
unfortunately because a jacquard EEE
不幸的是因为提花EEE
brand we won't be able to be quite that
品牌，我们将无法做到
easy going I do want to point out some
随和，我想指出一些
of the things that I see are showing
我看到的东西正在显示
that micro profile and jacquard EEE
微型轮廓和提花EEE
are not that far off first one is a rest
离那不远，第一个是休息
client the idea behind the type safe
客户安全类型背后的想法
rest client that's in micro profile it
在微型配置文件中的其他客户
actually came from several members of
实际上是来自
the jax-rs team but jax-rs was so far
jax-rs团队，但jax-rs到目前为止
along with her Java EE eight deliverable
连同她的Java EE 8可交付成果
there's no way that they could say oh
他们不可能说哦
hold up we want to put something in so
按住，我们想放点东西
some of the team members started in
一些团队成员开始于
micro profile and came up with the rest
微观概况，并提出其余
client so sometime down the road I'm not
客户，所以有时候我不是
going to claim exactly when but I could
打算确切地声明何时，但我可以
see the concept of the rest client
看到其余客户的概念
getting merged into the jax-rs spec at
被合并到jax-rs规范中
some point I mean right now they're at
我是说现在他们在
version 2.1 point two I don't know it
2.1版第二点我不知道
could be two point two maybe it's
可能是两点两，也许是
something more major maybe it's gonna be
更重要的事情可能会
down the road a little bit I don't know
一点点我不知道
but I see that there's a natural
但我看到有一种自然
progression from micro profile to
从微观轮廓发展到
Jakarta EE
雅加达EE
I had mentioned where micro profile was
我曾提到微观轮廓在哪里
never meant to be a standards
从来没有成为标准
organization we we had thought okay
我们认为还可以的组织
config micro propa micro profile config
配置微道具微配置文件
has been a very popular specification
一直是非常受欢迎的规范
and implementation so we
和实施，所以我们
pose that as a jsr this was before
摆成以前的jsr
Oracle decided they were going to move
甲骨文决定他们要搬家
Java EE and to eclipse so we have a
Java EE和日食，所以我们有一个
config jsr that is active they've
他们已经激活的配置jsr
produced a couple of early drafts of
产生了一些早期的草稿
their spec ok but now that we're making
他们的规格还可以，但现在我们正在
progress with our specification document
我们的规格文件进展
our specially specification process does
我们专门的规范过程
that make sense to continue with the jsr
继续使用jsr有意义
or should that effort now move over to
还是现在应该将精力转移到
the config specification underneath
下面的配置规范
Jakarta EE I have thrown it out to the
Jakarta EE我已经把它扔给了
config Jas our expert group and they're
配置Jas我们的专家组，他们是
discussing it whether or not they do it
讨论是否要这样做
I don't know yet but it is an idea that
我还不知道，但这是一个想法
they are taking a look at the reactive
他们正在看反应
platform I've mentioned a couple of
平台，我提到过几个
features that are being looked at for
正在寻找的功能
future revisions of Micra profile the
Micra配置文件的未来版本
reactive operators and reactive reactive
无功算子和无功
messaging this came about because this
之所以发消息是因为
this team from light Bend they wrote a
他们从光弯队写了一个
wonderful blog I don't know if you guys
很棒的博客，我不知道你们
have seen it or not I would take a look
看过没看我会看一下
at it if you I have questions about the
如果您对此有疑问，
relationship between Micah profile and
弥迦简介与
Jakarta EE this is a very good blog this
Jakarta EE这是一个非常好的博客
was written before they ever decided or
是在他们决定之前写的，或者
no maybe they did decide to move to
也许他们没有决定搬到
micro profile but it was just shortly
微观资料，但不久
afterwards but they talked about their
之后，但他们谈论了他们的
process of what did they want out of
他们想要什么的过程
this exercise and they were looking at
这个练习，他们在看
Jakarta EE and they were looking at Mike
雅加达EE，他们正在看Mike
a profile or do they continue on their
个人资料还是他们继续
own they had a lot of experience
自己，他们有很多经验
internal and how were they going to move
内部以及他们将如何移动
this forward so they decided on using
这个前进，所以他们决定使用
micro profile that's where they're
微型档案就是他们的所在
working they're working on these
他们正在努力工作
specifications but their longer-term
规格，但长期
goal is not only to get into Jakarta EE
目标不仅是进入雅加达EE
they're also proposing things for Java
他们也在为Java提出建议
SE they're trying to get their streams
SE他们正在努力获得他们的信息流
API supported by java SE so they are
Java SE支持API，因此它们是
continuing to move forward they would
继续前进，他们会
like to see it more in the mainstream
喜欢在主流中看到更多
with Java SE and Jakarta EE but they're
使用Java SE和Jakarta EE，但它们
starting with micro profile
从微观轮廓开始
another integration sort of if you want
如果需要的话，另一种集成方式
to call that or kind of a move we have
称呼我们有这样的举动
fault-tolerance within the programming
编程中的容错
model for micro profile and it's
微观轮廓模型
wonderful for you know having automatic
对您来说很棒，知道自动
timeouts the circuit breakers fallback
断路器回退超时
processing etc but it is a programming
处理等，但这是一个编程
model you have to modify your code in
模型，您必须在其中修改代码
order to get this capability well
为了很好地获得此功能
there's also the service mesh idea in
还有服务网格的想法
STL and they can do a lot of this same
STL，他们可以做很多同样的事情
type of mechanism by no modifications to
机制类型，无须修改
the code they do it by intercepting the
他们通过截获
calls between the different micro
不同微之间的通话
services now the only thing that they
现在服务他们唯一的
can't do is fall back processing because
不能做的是回退处理，因为
I really have no idea on how to do a
我真的不知道该怎么做
fall back processing so they can't do
回退处理，因此他们无法执行
that but the rest of them they can
那，但是他们其余的他们可以
actually do so how do we integrate these
实际上这样做我们如何整合这些
two if someone has developed
两个，如果有人发展
applications using our programming model
使用我们的编程模型的应用程序
and now it's being deployed into an sto
现在它被部署到一个仓库
environment you know how do those
你知道环境如何
mechanisms mesh how do they work
机制如何工作
together the reason that I put this one
在一起的原因，我把这个
up is because this kind of shows that
是因为这种显示
well maybe this isn't Jakarta EE now I'm
好吧，现在我不是Jakarta EE
not saying Jakarta EE isn't interested
并不是说Jakarta EE不感兴趣
in sto I mean maybe they are but right
在我的意思是也许他们是对的
now it's not so the idea here is like a
现在不是，这里的想法就像
profile maybe it's not all going in to
个人资料可能不全是
Jakarta EE it may depend on each of the
Jakarta EE可能取决于每个
individual components so I've kind of
个别组件，所以我有点
talked about the different communities I
谈到我的不同社区
think you guys have figured out I work
认为你们知道我在工作
in both communities I work on Jakarta EE
在两个社区中，我都从事Jakarta EE的工作
things I work on mica profile you see a
我在云母资料上工作的东西，你看到一个
lot of different companies up here I
我这里有很多不同的公司
even you know my word slip earlier with
甚至你也早知道我的话
Microsoft they're up here with Jakarta
微软，他们与雅加达在一起
EE
电子工程
if you look here on the micro profile
如果您在微观轮廓上看这里
community there Microsoft is over there
微软在那里
as well so we've got quite a set of
以及，所以我们有很多
projects and vendors and individuals I
项目，供应商和个人我
didn't get all the individual names onto
没有把所有的个人名字都放在
these charts I apologize if you are one
这些图表我很抱歉，如果你是一个
of them and so if you look at both
他们中的一个，所以如果你同时看这两个
communities you can see a lot of overlap
社区中您会看到很多重叠
and there in the middle those are all
在中间，这些都是
the companies that are very active or
那些非常活跃的公司或
company's projects vendors however you
公司的项目供应商，但是您
want to look at it all of these are very
想看看这一切，非常
active in the development of both micro
活跃于双方的发展
profile and Jakarta EEE
个人资料和雅加达EEE
we all want to see both of these succeed
我们都希望看到这两个成功
according to the current timeframe
根据当前时间
okay now even these other projects that
好吧，即使是其他项目，
I've kind of you know shaded out a
我有点你知道阴影
little bit I could see some of them
我可以看到其中的一些
moving over as well and as we continue
以及继续前进
to define this relationship between my
定义我之间的这种关系
micro profile and Jakarta EE and I want
微型个人资料和Jakarta EE，我想要
to point out you know of course both
指出你当然知道
under the guidance of the Eclipse
在Eclipse的指导下
Foundation so I know you know this isn't
基金会，所以我知道你知道这不是
a defined answer there was one guy I ran
一个明确的答案，我跑过一个人
into
进入
he said I can't make it to your session
他说我不能参加你的会议
you know give me the you know the one
你知道给我你知道一个
sentence conclusion and it's like I I
句子的结论，就像II
can't because there is no specific
不能因为没有特定的
defined solution for micro profile and
微观轮廓的定义解决方案
Jakarta EE I see it as taking some time
Jakarta EE我认为这需要一些时间
you can see a lot of the similarities
你会看到很多相似之处
you can see how we are working together
您可以看到我们如何一起工作
to try to come up with the right things
尝试提出正确的事情
but it will depend on the timing of
但这取决于时间
things related to config or fault
与配置或故障有关的事情
tolerance or these other components
公差或这些其他要素
within micro profile and how and when do
在微轮廓内以及如何以及何时执行
they merge in which occurred to EE but
他们合并到EE中发生，但是
we are definitely working together and
我们一定在合作，
we expect this relationship to continue
我们希望这种关系会继续下去
to evolve so that was that any questions
进化，所以有任何问题
yes okay so the question is the
是的，好的，问题是
specification process once it's
规范流程
finalized will it be the same for micro
最终确定是否与Micro相同
profile as it is for Jakarta EE is that
Jakarta EE的个人资料是
right no we have we have determined that
是的，没有，我们已经确定
the specification process is meant for
规范过程旨在
working groups and the working groups
工作组和工作组
you have to be a member of a working
你必须是一个工作的成员
group in order to participate in that
小组参加
specification process right now Micra
现在进行规格说明Micra
profile is not part of the jacquard EEE
轮廓不是提花EEE的一部分
working group I see it as a piecemeal so
我认为工作组是零散的
items like the config jsr the config
像jsr config这样的配置
could move over they could be a new
可能会过去，可能是新的
project under Jakarta ee and then they
在Jakarta ee下进行项目，然后他们
could follow the specification process
可以遵循规范流程
but like a profile with all of the
但就像所有
things that we're doing right now with
我们现在正在做的事情
our 17 component releases and our
我们的17个组件版本以及
platform releases we're going to
我们将要发布的平台
continue to use our current process
继续使用我们当前的流程
until those things start moving over to
直到这些东西开始转移到
Jakarta okay anything else yes okay so
雅加达好的，还有其他什么，好的，所以
is there any interest for
有兴趣吗
the big cloud providers let's see you
大型云服务提供商，让我们拭目以待
said Amazon and and Google right
说亚马逊和谷歌对
not directly oh okay so I do have to
不直接哦，好吧，我必须
close down here pretty quick but we have
在这里很快关闭，但是我们有
had some discussions with them with the
与他们进行了一些讨论
with the other companies but you know
与其他公司，但你知道
they haven't signed up to where they are
他们还没有签到他们在哪里
actually you know signed up either on
实际上您知道在
jacquard ee or micro profile there are
提花ee或微轮廓
discussions but nothing firm yet yeah so
讨论，但还没有确定，是的
just repeat that for the mic here
只需在这里为麦克风重复一下
Heiko pointed out that Microsoft has
Heiko指出微软已经
done work in this area for a juror to
在这方面做过陪审员
support micro profile so it's not your
支持微型个人资料，因此不是您的个人资料
Amazon and Google but they're pretty
亚马逊和谷歌，但他们很漂亮
good size cloud provider as well okay so
规模不错的云提供商也可以，所以
I got the hook so thank you very much
我明白了，非常感谢你
[Applause]
[掌声]